{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "1. How many types of nucleic acids are present in the living systems?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "One",
        "b": "Two",
        "c": "Three",
        "d": "Four"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. Which of the following most accurately describes the central dogma of biology?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "DNA to protein to RNA",
        "b": "Protein to RNA to DNA",
        "c": "RNA to protein to DNA",
        "d": "DNA to RNA to protein"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. Fill in the blanks, DNA is _______stranded while RNA is _______stranded",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Single, single",
        "b": "Single, double",
        "c": "Double, single",
        "d": "Double, double"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "4. DNA is the genetic material of the living systems that",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Stores information and passes to next generation",
        "b": "It is more stable than RNA",
        "c": "It has deoxyribose sugar",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "5. How many components are present in the basic unit of DNA?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "One",
        "b": "Two",
        "c": "Three",
        "d": "Four"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "6. EMSA stands for?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Electrophoretic mobility shift assay",
        "b": "Electrophoresis mobility shift assay",
        "c": "Electrophoretic mobilization shift assay",
        "d": "Electrophoresis mobilization shift assay"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "7. EMSA technique used for the interaction of the ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "DNA with the proteins",
        "b": "RNA with the proteins",
        "c": "Nucleic acids with the nucleic acid binding proteins",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "8. EMSA can determine the",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Binding affinity of the nucleic acid-protein",
        "b": "Can determine sequence specificity of the nucleic acid-protein interaction sites",
        "c": "Help in determination of kinetic and thermodynamic parameters",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "9. For performing EMSA what type of gel should be used?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Non-denaturing SDS-PAGE",
        "b": "Denaturing SDS-PAGE",
        "c": "NATIVE",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "10. In an EMSA experiment free DNA is separated from the protein-DNA complexes in a native gel by which following principle?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Molecular weight",
        "b": "Charge",
        "c": "DNA digestion with DNAse",
        "d": "Antibody immunoprecipitation"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
  ]
}
